We all would prefer to only find critical
vulnerabilities when all you have to do is open
a URL and a command executes. Five digits payout
please. But the truth is that we will keep finding
bugs with some prerequisites that downgrade
them to medium or even low risk. I admit that
I am sometimes tempted to not report a low risk
vulnerability but then I realize that even $100
or $200 for maybe an hour of writing a report
is still just too good to just throw away. In
today's video, I will show you a few simple rules
that I follow when reporting lows and mediums to
get the maximum payout. We'll use the example
of my recent $2,000 report in Stripe. Enjoy!
The first thing that I recommend you is to work
with the program, not against the program. I
know that you report vulnerabilities to make
bounty and so do I. This is my main goal. But
when writing the report, literally imagine the
customer of the company you are reporting to.
How they can get harmed? And write this in
the report. Don't write the report about a
hypothetical user but write about the very user
of this company and what can happen with them.
With that said, you should be working with
the team but you should not expect the team
to work with you. You should expect that
the triager will not make any work more
than necessary to process your report. Assume
they won't fix your minimal errors in your
proof of concept or in your explanation.
Sometimes, of course, they do, but often,
they don't have too much time to process your
report so they will do it as quickly as possible.
So don't assume they will like cooperate with
you but assume that you have to do all the work
yourself. And sometimes, that will not be the
case and then you will be positively surprised.
The second thing is to not treat the triagers or
the team as idiots and don't try to trick them
into triaging your report with higher severity
than it actually deserves. Because if you set too
high severity, they will just, first, treat you
as someone that's not so serious or not competent,
and they might downgrade the risk of your
report even lower than it actually should be.
If your vulnerability has some limitations,
let's say an unlikely user interactions,
where, for example, the user has to click
three times, acknowledge this in the report.
Imagine what would you say if you were the
triager and you would try to downgrade your
own report. Think about all the arguments that you
could use and try to address them while writing
the report. Because if you don't do this, what
will happen is the triager will think about it
anyway. At some point, the triager will reply
to you asking for these things and then you
have to address them anyway. And you are in much
better position if you address them straight away.
This gives the triager the information that you
are aware of those limitations but you reported
the bug anyway. And probably, the triager won't
get back to you with your own arguments. Instead,
the triager is more forced to ask the team if
they want to triage the vulnerability which has
lower risk level because of these prerequisites.
Of course, this won't magically help you with
too many prerequisites. For example, if a program
doesn't accept XSSes without CSP bypasses, if you
address this in your report, they won't magically
triage your bug just because of that. But also,
if you don't put this in your report, neither they
will accept the report. So you pretty much can't
lose on this. Hoping that someone will not notice
those prerequisites, I think it's just naive.
I'm definitely guilty of writing a lazy report
when I know the bug is not worth much. But it's
still too much for me to just throw away if I
already found the bug and all I have to do is
report it. This often bites back because when I
write a lazy report, as I called it, it comes back
to me with "Needs more info", with some questions
or with whatever and I end up wasting more time
and much more emotions - unnecessary emotions
- than I would if I would just sit, spend more
time initially on really good report and the bug
would be processed without going back and forth.
That's also the reason why I am leaning
more towards better paying programs where,
of course, I will find less bugs and write
less reports but they are worth more because
the minimum payout of, for example,
$500, really makes it worth the time.
What do I mean by a good report? I mean a
report where you show the reproduction steps
from the ground - from the level zero. Because
you have to be aware that the triager probably
will not know the application as well as you
do. The company to which you report the bug,
of course, they will know it better than you
but the triager may work on multiple programs
at the same time and the triager just won't
know every single application in and out. So
try to reset your knowledge and start with the
very simple steps like installation of tools,
setting up the environment, creating an account
and go from there. It's also a good practice to
simply test your vulnerability one more time
when creating a report because sometimes you
will then find out that you made some mistake and
maybe you don't want to report this bug anyway.
It's also worth to attach any code that will help
the triager or the program to reproduce the issue.
For example, a python proof of concept if that's
something more complex. If you don't know how to
write code in Python, in BBRE Premium, there is
a whole series of articles about using python for
security - for reproducing issues, working with
HTTP, headless browser and so on and so forth.
If there's a client-side issue that that you're
reporting, probably you want to create some HTML.
Maybe just send an HTML but also, a nice tool that
I've used a few times is codesandbox where you,
like, host the web app on the platform. And
also, record demos. For simple demos where it's
only a gif, I use LiceCAP because it's very quick.
And for more complex vulnerabilities, I sometimes
just use OBS - open broadcaster software and I
can even record a voiceover if that's necessary.
Hi team, I decided to record a demo because
there are a lot of moving parts. So first,
here on, the left hand side, I have
my DNS server that will return to...
Since I finished my challenge of 100 hours on
Stripe, I regularly still check new features
every month when I receive the newsletter from
them. And a few months ago, they added something
called Stripe Apps which is like an extension
of Stripe. The way it works is it works in an
iframe and, for example, you can quickly export
some files into a Google Drive or into Dropbox.
At the moment, it's still in beta version and
it's not yet possible to publish my own app for
other users. I think at the moment, Stripe still
has to approve manually every single application.
However, it's clear from the documentation that
in the future, users will be able to create and
share apps to the marketplace. My report affected
Apps and the attack scenario included creating a
malicious app. And I mentioned this fact in the
report that, at the moment, it's not even possible
to publish my app to other users. But this subject
wasn't even touched upon in any message apart from
the initial one from me. And the truth is that
an immature program in this moment could say:
"this bug"
"not affect users"
"Needs more info"
But here, it wasn't the case. I think most mature
programs like Stripe are happy that we report bugs
in alpha and beta versions because, for one, they
don't have to investigate if the bug was exploited
in the wild or it wasn't because it's not
published for users. But it's clear it will be.
And the way it functions is that it's an iframe
- the app is an iframe but it's a Sandbox and
it's well separated from the parent site. My
initial attack vector that I wanted to try was to
exfiltrate some unauthorized data by a malicious
Stripe App but I was not successful with this.
But then, I stepped back a little bit and I
noticed that if I put a login and password fields
in my application, LastPass or other password
managers can autofill my credentials into the App.
Then, a malicious app could send these plaintext credentials to the App's server and login
as the victim, giving an account takeover.
But the truth is that this bug is more
fault of password managers because, from the
browser's perspective, the iframe separation
between Stripe normal page and
Stripe App was as good as it can be.
Then why didn't I report this bug to password
managers and instead to Stripe? The truth is
I did report this bug to one of the password
managers a few months ago and it was marked as
duplicate of a won't fix bug from an internal
assessment from a few years ago. They said that
they accept the risk of that and I kinda assumed
that other password managers also know about this.
And I didn't try to hide this fact in my report,
hoping that Stripe or the triage will not notice
this. I made it very clear in the report that I
think it's more of a fault of a password managers.
But Stripe is in a hard position here because
they can't say that it's user's responsibility
or password manager's responsibility because
likely, this will not protect Stripe users.
The result? No going back and forth,
no needs more info status and instead,
$2,000 payout as a medium risk bug.
The way they fixed it is they removed
the autocomplete attribute and they
disallow password type input field so
that there is no way that password managers
autofill credentials of any Stripe users.
Stripe was actually the first program to which
I dedicated more time. About one year ago,
I challenged myself to spend 100 hours there.
If you want to see what bugs did I find and
how much money I made, check out this two-part
video that's on your screen right now. For
now, thank you for watching and goodbye!